Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm 5863 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 12)
  - 0466. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (N). Lorton, Burt. 12 pages., 1922-1925; 15 (Reel 12)
    People: Burt Lorton; James A. Finch; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0478. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (O). MacDonald, J.A.. 6 pages., 1923; 16 (Reel 12)
    People: J.A. MacDonald. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0484. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (P). McKinnon, Charles H.. 7 pages., 1923; 17 (Reel 12)
    People: Charles H. McKinnon; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World.
  - 0491. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (Q). Rowan, James. 9 pages., 1923; 18 (Reel 12)
    People: James Rowan; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners and censorship of mail.
  - 0500. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (R). Sheridan, Don. 7 pages., 1923; 19 (Reel 12)
    People: Don Sheridan. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0507. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (S). Sinclair, Archie. 40 pages., 1922-1923; 20 (Reel 12)
    People: Archie Sinclair; William J. Burns; James A. Finch; Pierce C. Wetter; Augustus T. Seymour; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Robe Carl White. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0547. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (T). Slovick, James. 16 pages., 1923-1944; 21 (Reel 12)
    People: James Slovick; Roger N. Baldwin; Daniel M. Lyons; Isaac Shorr. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; American Civil Liberties Union; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0563. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (U). Thompson, James P.. 9 pages., 1923; 22 (Reel 12)
    People: James P. Thompson; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0572. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (V). Turner, John L.. 8 pages., 1923; 23 (Reel 12)
    People: John L. Turner. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0580. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. Political Prisoners. Haywood Case. 337 pages., 1920-1923; 24 (Reel 12)
    People: Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; Charles F. Clyne; Albert DeSilver; Morris Hillquit; William D. Haywood. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; lists of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners and summaries of cases; foreign and domestic precedents for a decree of general amnesty for political prisoners; partial transcript of trial on appeal in case against William D. Haywood, et al. File folder omitted.
  - 0917. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (S). Archie Sinclair. Previously Restricted Materials. 28 pages., 1923; 25 (Reel 12)
    People: Archie Sinclair; Charlotte Anita Whitney. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports regarding Industrial Workers of the World activities in San Francisco, California; union organization state criminal syndicalism laws; Industrial Workers of the World fund raising and legal defense efforts.
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 13)
  - 0001. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. General. 353 pages., 1920-1923; 1 (Reel 13)
    People: James A. Finch; Elmer Anderson; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; A. Mitchell Palmer; Robert P. Stewart; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Newton D. Baker; Robert H. Turner; Ralph M. Easley; John W. Preston; Robert Duncan; Archibald Stevenson; Frank H. Rudkin; frank M. Silva; Anna C. Pollok; Theodora Pollok Rhoads; Charles M. Fickert; Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Gilson Gardner; George Wharton Pepper; Elbert Coutts; Edward Anderson. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union; National Civic Federation; Industrial Workers of the World publications and legal defense efforts; district attorney for the city and county of San Francisco, California; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0354. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Anderson, Elmer. 7 pages., 1923; 2 (Reel 13)
    People: Elmer Anderson; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0361. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. de Bernardi, Pete. 27 pages., 1920-1923; 3 (Reel 13)
    People: Pete De Bernardi; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Roger N. Baldwin; John W. Preston; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of the Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union.
  - 0388. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Brewer, Harry. 13 pages., 1923; 4 (Reel 13)
    People: Harry Brewer; Warren G, Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0401. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Hood, William. 17 pages., 1920-1923; 5 (Reel 13)
    People: William Hood; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0418. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Connellan, Robert. 18 pages., 1920-1933; 6 (Reel 13)
    People: Robert Connellan; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0436. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Downing, Mortimer. 16 pages., 1920-1923; 7 (Reel 13)
    People: Mortimer Downing; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0452. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Gray, Harry. 18 pages., 1920-1923; 8 (Reel 13)
    People: Harry Gray; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0470. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Grave, John. 18 pages., 1920-1923; 9 (Reel 13)
    People: John Grave; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0488. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Hammer, Henry. 28 pages., 1920-1923; 10 (Reel 13)
    People: Henry Hammer; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; Frank B. Kellogg; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0516. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Elliott, Frank. 15 pages., 1923; 11 (Reel 13)
    People: Frank Elliott; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0531. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Luber, Chris A.. 15 pages., 1923; 12 (Reel 13)
    People: Chris A. Luber; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0546. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. McLaughlin, Phil. 22 pages., 1923; 13 (Reel 13)
    People: Phil McLaughlin; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0568. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. O'Connell, George. 14 pages., 1920-1923; 14 (Reel 13)
    People: George O'Connell; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0582. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Potthast, John. 16 pages., 1920-1923; 15 (Reel 13)
    People: John Potthast; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World penitentiary.
  - 0598. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Quigley, Edward. 85 pages., 1922-1923; 16 (Reel 13)
    People: Edward Quigley; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Mary Gertrude Fendall; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty; William J. Burns. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0683. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Quigley, Edward. Previously Restricted Materials. 7 pages., 1922- 1923; 17 (Reel 13)
    People: Edward Quigley; William J. Burns; Harry Weinberger. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports on physicians qualified to examine Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; Socialist Party of America.
  - 0690. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Quinlan, James. 14 pages., 1920-1923; 18 (Reel 13)
    People: James Quinlan; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John_ Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0704. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Santilli, Vincent. 34 pages., 1920-1924; 19 (Reel 13)
    People: Vincent Santilli; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations.
  - 0737. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Sprague, Myron. 13 pages., 1920-1923; 20 (Reel 13)
    People: Myron Sprague; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0750. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Tabib, Caesar. 101 pages., 1922-1923; 21 (Reel 13)
    People: Caesar Tabib; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Frank H. Rudkin; Robert Duncan; George B. Christian, Jr.; Harry M. Daugherty; William J. Burns; Roger N. Baldwin; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; Workers National Prison Comfort Club.
  - 0851. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Tabib, Caesar. Previously Restricted Materials. 5 pages., 1921- 1922; 22 (Reel 13)
    People: Caesar Tabib; Roger N. Baldwin; Alexander S. Lanier. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports on physicians qualified to examine Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union.
  - 0856. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Tori, Jacob. 19 pages., 1920-1924; 23 (Reel 13)
    People: Jacob Tori; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; Alexander S. Lanier; Harry M. Daugherty; Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations.
  - 0875. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Voetter, George F. 17 pages., 1920-1923; 24 (Reel 13)
    People: George F. Voetter; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0892. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Price, James. 90 pages., 1922-1924; 25 (Reel 13)